Guide to the Robert Richardson Sears Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1986-046
  - Irwin ratings - parental inhibition (Box 15, Folder 65)
  - Staff meetings, 1944 (Box 15, Folder 66)
  - Allport war chapter (Box 15, Folder 67)
  - Psycholanalytical tests - speech notes (Box 15, Folder 68)
  - Public lectures (Box 15, Folder 69)
  - F-A criticism (Box 15, Folder 70)
  - Rosenzweig's frustration test (Box 15, Folder 71)
  - SSRC committee on gifted children, 1976-1978 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - ----------------------- (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Typescripts: "Erickson on America: Childhood and Society and National Identity," 1981; and IV "The State of the Art (re child development; begins on page 72)" (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Society of Experimental Psychologies (rosters and minutes), 1981, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Information on human sexual development (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence (alphabetized but not by year) (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Center for Advanced Study in Behavioral Science, 1969-1972 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Fellows (CASBS), 1971-1972 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Year at Center (A-H), 1968-1969 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Year at Center (I-Z), 1968-1969 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - CASBS (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Trustees' information I CASBS (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Trustees' information II CASBS (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Reviews and comments (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - References (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - New reviewers (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - UNESCO conference in San Francisco, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Dissertation schedules, 1967-1969 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: B (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: C (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: G (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: P (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Wexler, Alice (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Dollplay - original protocols, 1-451, 1951-1952 (Box 16)
  - Problem situations - 1-60, 101-153, 300-349, 401-451 (Box 16)
  - Deviation I and II. Cambridge study - Pauline Sears, 1951 (Box 16)
  - R. R. Sears correspondence: A, circa 1953-1961 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - R. R. Sears correspondence: B, circa 1953-1961 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - R. R. Sears correspondence: C, circa 1953-1961 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - R. R. Sears correspondence: D, circa 1953-1961 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - R. R. Sears correspondence: E, circa 1953-1961 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - R. R. Sears correspondence: F, circa 1953-1961 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - R. R. Sears correspondence: G, circa 1953-1961 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - R. R. Sears correspondence: H, circa 1953-1961 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - R. R. Sears correspondence: I, circa 1953-1961 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - R. R. Sears correspondence: J, circa 1953-1961 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - R. R. Sears correspondence: K, circa 1953-1961 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - R. R. Sears correspondence: L, circa 1953-1961 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - R. R. Sears correspondence: M, circa 1953-1961 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - R. R. Sears correspondence: N, circa 1953-1961 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - R. R. Sears correspondence: O, circa 1953-1961 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - R. R. Sears correspondence: P, circa 1953-1961 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - R. R. Sears correspondence: Q, circa 1953-1961 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - R. R. Sears correspondence: R, circa 1953-1961 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - R. R. Sears correspondence: S, circa 1953-1961 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - R. R. Sears correspondence: T, circa 1953-1961 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - R. R. Sears correspondence: U, circa 1953-1961 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - R. R. Sears correspondence: V, circa 1953-1961 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - R. R. Sears correspondence: W, circa 1953-1961 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - R. R. Sears correspondence: XYZ, circa 1953-1961 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Human relations area files (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Mathematical research in behavioral sciences (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Preliminary plan rehabilitation center, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Smith, Henrietta T. (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Shaplin, Judson T. (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - Sanger, Marjorie (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - Palfrey House (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - McCord research (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - Littman, Richard A. (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - International Congress - Brussels, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - APA survey of doctroal programs, 1950-1951 (Box 17, Folder 35)
  - Harris, Dale B. (Box 17, Folder 36)
  - Greenwald, Hal (Box 17, Folder 37)
  - Cutts, Jeanette (Box 17, Folder 38)
  - Contemporary psychology (Box 17, Folder 39)
  - Bremer, Gloria J. (Box 17, Folder 40)
  - Bingham lecture (Box 17, Folder 41)
  - Social Science Research Council (Box 17, Folder 42)
  - APA committee on relations with psychiatry (Box 17, Folder 43)
  - Editoral reviews, 1954-1959 (Box 17, Folder 44)
  - Committee on freedom of enquiry (Box 17, Folder 45)
  - Self-study committee (Box 17, Folder 46)
  - Joint committee on mental illness and health (Box 17, Folder 47)
  - Rapaport, David, 1942-1946 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Iowa Child Welfare Research Station, S, 1942-1949 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Iowa Child Welfare Research Station, I, 1942-1949 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Iowa Child Welfare Research Station, V, 1942-1949 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Iowa Child Welfare Research Station, W, 1942-1949 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Iowa Child Welfare Research Station, X,Y,Z, 1942-1949 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Micellaneous filing, 1949 May-June (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - RRS trip east, 1944 February (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Smith, Afton, 1944-1946 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Youtz, May P., 1946 October (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Updegraff, Ruth, 1943 June (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Ojemann, Ralph H., 1943-1949 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Meredeth, Howard V., 1942-1946 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Wellman, Beth, 1948 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Preschool education, 1946 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Confidential reports to President Hancher, 1943 October-September (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Hovland-consultant, 1944 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Dissertation summaries, 1941-1942 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Flexible gunnery, 1950 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Reports issued from AC-94 (Iowa project), 1945-1956 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Informal memos - (Ms.), 1945 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Final report to prime contractor on OEMsr 1171, subcontract no. 1, the State University of Iowa, 1945 September 18 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - OSRD [Office of Scientific Research and Development] report "Target Method" (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Phone log, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Office of Scientific Research and Development, correspondence, 1944 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Wisconsin - National Research Council travel blanks (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Office of Scientific Research and Development - Salina project. SUI (State Universit of Iowa) subcontract, 1944-1945 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Wisconsin project, 1944 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Office of Scientific Research and Development - Salina project, personnel, 1944-1945 (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Office of Scientific Research and Development - Salina project, purchasing, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Office of Scientific Research and Development - Salina project, statements of account, 1945-1946 (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Office of Scientific Research and Development - Salina project, classified receipts, 1945-1947 (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Salina - correspondence - general, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Salina - W. J. Brogden (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - Salina - Edwin B. Knauft (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - Osgood, Charles (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - Salina - Ruth Phillips (Box 18, Folder 37)
  - Purdy, Donald M. (Box 18, Folder 38)
  - Tuzzolino, Grace and Harvey, Mildred (Box 18, Folder 39)
  - R. R. Sears correspondence at Salina (Box 18, Folder 40)
  - Station wagon (Box 18, Folder 41)
  - Warehouse receipts - Salina (Box 18, Folder 42)
  - Selective Service deferment blanks (Box 18, Folder 43)
  - OSRD - reports (Box 18, Folder 44)
  - Clearance questionnaires (Box 18, Folder 45)
  - Western Union telegrams (Box 18, Folder 46)
  - OSRD Project: Miscellany from campus report, 1945 March (Box 18, Folder 47)
  - 2nd Air Force - Gunnery (Tucker) (Box 18, Folder 48)
  - Notes on On-Target development (Box 18, Folder 49)
  - On-Target method: reports, etc. (Box 18, Folder 50)
  - Photographs - restricted (Box 18, Folder 51)
  - SHAAF memos (Box 18, Folder 52)
  - NRC committee on child development, 1948-1950 (Box 18, Folder 53)
  - Harvard correspondence up to June 1949 (Box 18, Folder 54)
  - Society for Research in Child Development, 1947-1950 (Box 18, Folder 55)
  - American Parents' committee, 1948 September - 1949 September (Box 18, Folder 56)
  - APA Board of Directors (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Harvard teaching (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - American Psychology Association (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - APA - confidential (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - RRS - alphabethical files, A-F, circa 1930-1939 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - RRS - alphabethical files, G-H, circa 1930-1939 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - RRS - alphabethical files, I-Z, circa 1930-1939 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Brogden, W. J. (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Bursary assistants (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - A (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - B (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Connecticut personnel department (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Council on human relations (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Connecticut vocational rehabilitation (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - C (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - D (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Davis, Gordon (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Department of psychology (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - E (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Eastern Psychological Association (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Erickson, M. H. (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - F (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - G (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Godbeer, Elizabeth (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - H (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Hunt's book (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - I (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Iowa Child Welfare Research Station (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Iowa budget (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Iowa City (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - J (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Jones, M. R. (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - K (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - Kornreich, Jerome (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - L (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - M (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - May, Mark A. (Box 19, Folder 37)
  - Mc-Mac (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - Melton, Arthur W. (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - McGeogh, John A. (Box 19, Folder 40)
  - N (Box 19, Folder 41)
  - O (Box 19, Folder 42)
  - Orbison, William (Box 19, Folder 43)
  - P (Box 19, Folder 44)
  - Q (Box 19, Folder 45)
  - R (Box 19, Folder 46)
  - Recommendations (Box 19, Folder 47)
  - Rosenzweig, S. (Box 19, Folder 48)
  - S (Box 19, Folder 49)
  - Snedden (Box 19, Folder 50)
  - SSRC (Box 19, Folder 51)
  - T (Box 19, Folder 52)
  - U (Box 19, Folder 53)
  - V (Box 19, Folder 54)
  - W (Box 19, Folder 55)
  - Wendt, C. R. (Box 19, Folder 56)
  - War psychology (Box 19, Folder 57)
  - XYZ (Box 19, Folder 58)
  - Correspondence, circa 1951-1953 (Box 20)
    - Cobb, Katherine (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Fahy, Kathleen (Dorman) (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Faigin, Helen (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Gewirtz, J. L. (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Keppel, Francis (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Levin, Harry (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Lowell, Edgar L. (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - McKee, John (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Scott, J. P. (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Swift, Joan W. (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - "Schmidt case" (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - A (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - B (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - C (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - D (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - E (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - F (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - G (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - H (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - I (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - J (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - K (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - L (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - M (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - N (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - O (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - P (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - Q-R (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - S (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - T (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - U-V (Box 20, Folder 31)
    - W (Box 20, Folder 32)
    - XYZ (Box 20, Folder 33)
    - American Psychological Association (Box 20, Folder 34)
    - American Psychological Association - President (Box 20, Folder 35)
    - Committee on training in clinical psychology (Box 20, Folder 36)
    - National Research Council: Committee on child development, 1950-1951 (Box 20, Folder 37)
    - National Research Council: Children's bureau of advisory committee, 1949-1951 (Box 20, Folder 38)
    - Wolfe (Box 20, Folder 39)
    - APA - Committee correspondence on Executive Secretary, 1950 (Box 20, Folder 40)
    - Heiser, Karl (Box 20, Folder 41)
    - APA - Executive Secretary, 1950-1951 (Box 20, Folder 42)
    - APA - Division of personality and social psychology (Box 20, Folder 43)
    - APA - Board meeting, 1951 March 1-4 (Box 20, Folder 44)
  - Iowa Child Welfare Research Station - A, 1942-1949 (Box 20, Folder 45)
  - ICWRS - B, 1942-1949 (Box 20, Folder 46)
  - ICWRS - C, 1942-1949 (Box 20, Folder 47)
  - ICWRS - D, 1942-1949 (Box 20, Folder 48)
  - ICWRS - E, 1942-1949 (Box 20, Folder 49)
  - ICWRS - F, 1942-1949 (Box 20, Folder 50)
  - ICWRS - G, 1942-1949 (Box 20, Folder 51)
  - ICWRS - H, 1942-1949 (Box 20, Folder 52)
  - Hunt (Handbook) correspondence (Box 20, Folder 53)
  - ICWRS - I, 1942-1949 (Box 20, Folder 54)
  - ICWRS - J, 1942-1949 (Box 20, Folder 55)
  - ICWRS - K, 1942-1949 (Box 20, Folder 56)
  - ICWRS - L, 1942-1949 (Box 20, Folder 57)
  - ICWRS - M, 1942-1949 (Box 20, Folder 58)
  - ICWRS - Mc, 1942-1949 (Box 20, Folder 59)
  - Miller, Herbert C. (Box 20, Folder 60)
  - ICWRS - N, 1942-1949 (Box 20, Folder 61)
  - Nowlis, Vincent (Box 20, Folder 62)
  - ICWRS - O, 1942-1949 (Box 20, Folder 63)
  - ICWRS - P, 1942-1949 (Box 20, Folder 64)
  - ICWRS - R, 1942-1949 (Box 20, Folder 65)
  - APA committee of department chairmen (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - APA election committee (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - American Psychological Foundation (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - SSRC committee on child development (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - SSRC committee on personality development (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - SSRC - social behavior research, 1952-1953 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Committee on socialization (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - SSRC - socialization committee, 1951-1953 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Medical curriculum (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Medical school facilities planning (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Academic council (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Agenda: SSRC meeting of the Board of Directors, 1953 September 15-18 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - SSRC - emotional growth (Box 22, Folder 5)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1989-162
  - SearI s annual report; Art History Faculty Retreat; SRCD-Reports; Final Report-SRCD NSF NHPRC; Finance Ccrnmittee-SRCD; Co~ence 1985-1988 (Box 1)
  - Co~ence: 1974-1984 (Box 2)
  - Conunittee on Aging; Biography: Mark Twain; Mark Twain drafts; Hamilton CravenI s papers (Box 3)
  - HAAN folders (2); 2 Haan books (Box 4)
  - Mark Twain Exhibitionism papers; SRCD; Correspondence (Box 5)
  - Correspondence; Budget; Research plans (Box 6)
  - BEM papers; Edwards data; ACH tests; Reprints (Box 7)
  - Aggression factor analysis; Instruments; Jennings political socialization (Box 8)
  - Congressional investigation; The 3 R IS; Class infonnation (Box 9)
  - NIMH-p:ro:Jralll research proposal; Models for family research; Speeches; Psychological study needs (Box 10)
  - Newton study memoranda; Achievement mativation (Box 11)
  - Newton follow up (Box 12)
  - Newton follow up (Box 13)
  - Newton follow up; Doll study (Box 14)
  - Doll study (Box 15)
  - Doll study (Box 16)
  - Doll study (Box 17)
  - Grants; classnotes (Box 18)
  - Grants; classnotes (Box 19)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1989-174
  - Miscellaneous files: English -Headship; Budget reports; Rochester Conference; Files: "A" -General (Box 1)
  - Files: "A" (cant'd) -''H'' (Box 2)
  - Files: "I" -"R" (Box 3)
  - Files: ''R'' -"s" (Box 4)
  - Files: "s" (cont'd) (Box 5)
  - Files: "s" (cont'd) (Box 6)
  - Files: "s" (cont'd) (Box 7)
  - Files: "S" (cont'd) -end (Box 8)
  - Personal files; Date books (Box 9)
  - Mark Twain research notes and papers (Box 10)
  - Mark Twain research notes and papers (Box 11)
  - Mark Twain research notes and papers (Box 12)
  - Mark Twain research notes and papers (Box 13)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1993-063
  - Sears: Vita, publications, memoranda on identification (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - References, 1949-50 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Recommendation letters, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence files with or concerning his Harvard students, 1949-52
    - Blane, Howard T. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Brush, Elinor Sacks (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Cowen, Judith (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Herrick, Marvin W (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Hyde, Elizabeth (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Johnson, Elizabeth Z. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Kincannon, Mary E. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Koenitsberg, Miss (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Kuhns, Roger (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Latham, Charles Gilbert (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Libby, Anne K. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - MacLeech, Bert (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Murchie, Guy (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Nagy, Marie (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Olson, Claire (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Price, Betty E. Murray (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Rosenblith, Judy F. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Shane, John Stewart (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Shimbel, Constance (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Tyson, Bob (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Wang, Shuen Shan (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Williamson, Mae (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Wisner, Emma Oriole (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Wohlwill, Joachin (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Harvard University Press, Board of Syndics (minutes, agenda, reports), 1951-52 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - American Psychological Association (minutes, agenda), 1951-52 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - American Psychological Association (minutes, agenda), 1951-52 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - American Psychological Association, general (memoranda, correspondence, bulletin), 1951-52 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Social Science Research Council, Committee on Research in Social Behavior, 1951-52 (correspondence and reports) (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Harvard correspondence files, 1949-52:
    - A (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - B (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - C (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - D (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - E (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - F (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - G (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - H (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - J (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - K (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - L (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - M (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - N (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - O (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - P (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Q-R (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - S (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - T (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - U-V (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - W (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - XYZ (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous files:
    - Mailing lists (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Popular dissemination plans, 1952 (correspondence with Parents' Magazine) (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Visiting committee, Harvard graduate school of education (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Sample forms (Harvard preschool) (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Evaluation of elementary education programs, 1952 (student reports) (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Group positive and negative attention observations, 1952 (student reports) (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Social class (Sears' notes on) (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Professional contracts and certificates, 1931-67 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Sears' bibliography (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Press notices on Sears (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Articles by Sears (including autobiographical/family history) (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Dictaphone record (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Bird watching notes (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Hamilton Cravens: correspondence re history committee of SRCD, 1996 (ACCN 96-121) (Box 3, Folder 20)